ANDREW NOONAN

215-292-5083 | andrew@noonan.cc

SUMMARY

Over 10 years of experience as an engineer, manager, and technical lead. Recently I have worked as lead for large scale projects; working with internal and external cross-functional teams to architect, build, and bring products to market. I am interested in capitalizing on my diverse experience to build and execute a product roadmap with a relatively small and agile team.

SKILLS

Software Engineering, Systems Architecture, API Design Product Management & Development, Project Management Java, Python, Node, C++, SQL, Cassandra, Redis, Lucene

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

NOVEMBER 2015 – JANUARY 2020

Technical Lead Manager, Senior Partner Engineer, Uber

- Technical lead and system architect for Uber Money's banking product
- Lead engineering effort for \$3.7 Billion merger with Yandex.taxi in Russia
- Delivered react native clone of the Uber rider app in Russia to ~10 million users in under 10 months managing a cross functional team of internal and external stakeholders
- Designed and launched Uber/Google Maps integration to ~5 million riders
- Co-designed Google OpenID authentication protocol for use in integration

JANUARY 2015 - NOVEMBER 2015

Head of Partner Engineering, Asana

- Fostered relationships with large organizations such as Slack and Atlassian to extend Asana's product reach through integrations
- Prioritized engineering and product asks from external partners
- Worked closely with the CEO and other leaders in the company to prioritize internal and external product roadmaps to enable integrations

MAY 2014 - JANUARY 2015

Senior Partner Engineer, Twitter

- Helped design and launch mobile attribution platform for Twitter ads
- Managed technical relationships with all major industry mobile ads tracking platforms

DECEMBER 2011 - MAY 2014

Software Engineer, Head of Partner Engineering, Gnip

- Developed business plan for and launched Partner Engineering team at Gnip
- Increased revenue of strategic partnerships through technical optimizations and tighter product feedback loops
- Developed highly concurrent backend web applications in Java and RoR
- Designed and implemented geo location and language detection algorithms with >20,000 rps

SEPTEMBER 2009 - DECEMBER 2011

Software Engineer, Lockheed Martin

- Co-developed award winning geospatial functionality on a tactical display framework in Java
- Directed a team of developers through the refactoring of a group based permissioning system to control access to Java and C++ applications and backend functions
- Engineered TCP/IP packet based communication between C++ and Java applications
- Held a Top Secret clearance from the United States Department of Defense

EDUCATION

Graduated 2009

University of Colorado at Boulder- Boulder, Colorado Bachelor of Science, Computer Science Engineering major, Computer Engineering minor Engineering and Applied Science Dean's List Elected President of the Engineering School

Graduated 2005

William Penn Charter School - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania High School Diploma, May 2005 Graduated with academic honors, AP Calculus, Physics, and Chemistry score 4/5